DIEGO CASAL LORENZO

Academic Portfolio Web | dcasal.github.io

E-mail adress | d.casal.lorenzo@gmail.com

Phone number | Japanse 080 - 4834 - 5982



PROFILE

Hi, my name is Diego, I was born in Vigo, Galicia, on the northwest of Spain. I moved to Barcelona at 18 years old to study architecture. There I developed a great interest, not only in this discipline, but also in graphic design and photography.

If I had to highlight something that I have learned through my years studying and working is that nor architecure, nor any other discipline, is absolute. Quite the contrary, every one of them is made up of numerous and diverse subjects, and when placed properly altogether, they acquire a purpose.

Is with this thought in mind that I stay motivated and face every challenge, doing my best to arrange the needed pieces together and find the optimal outcome for any given situation.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree & Masters in Architecture

Escola Tènica Superior d'Arquitectura de Barcelona (ETSAB)

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya 2011 - 2019 | Barcelona, Spain

BIM Practical Application on Construction Projects using Revit - Certificate

70hrs course - Fundación Laboral de la Construcción 2021 | Vigo, Spain

& CERTIFICATES

Digital Content Creation - Certificate

320hrs course - Escuela de Organización Industrial (EOI) 2019 | Vigo, Spain

Introductory course to C# programming and its application to Unity software for digital content creation:

- Basic C# programming with Visual Studio.
- Introduction to Unity 3D, modelling and level design.
- Application of C# scripts to provide functionalities.
- Development of different case studies.

EXPERIENCE

Fundació Temple Expiatori de la SAGRADA FAMILIA Intern Architect

June 2018 - July 2019 | Barcelona, Spain

Tasks:

- Use of 2D drawing software for blueprints and project documentation
- Use of 3D modeling software for architectonic elements
- Construction site visiting

ALTURA | Architecture Office

Architectural designer and engineer

November 2021 - December 2023 | Andorra la Vella, Andorra

Sustainable mountain architecture and lanscape.

Tasks:

- Project design and drawing| Residencial buildings, dwellings and Passive House | Landscaping
- BIM methodology implementation for architectural projects
- Blueprint and documentation drafting
- Use of 3D design software for architectural modeling
- Use of 2D drawig software for drafting
- Construction site supervision and managment
- Construction work budget reviewing
- Managment of everyday relations with collaborating and subcontracted companies

PROFICENCY

LANGUAGES

Native | Spanish, Galician

Fluent | English, Catalan

Beginner | Japanese

SOFTWARE

3D/2D modeling & drawing

Rhinoceros 3D | Grasshopper | V-Ray | AutoCAD

BIM (Building Information Modeling)

Allplan | Revit

Graphic design

Photoshop | Illustrator

Programming

C# | Unity | HTML | CSS

Document drafting

InDesign | Microsoft Office